Guide to the Rachel Carson Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1921-79; Series I; 44; (101 boxes)
  - SILENT SPRING
    - Manuscripts
      - Notes
        - Tobacco, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 888)
        - Toxicity, 1957-61 (Box 46, Folder 889)
        - Water pollution, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 890)
        - Wildlife, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 891)
        - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 892)
      - Notebooks, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 893-94)
      - Bibliographical files, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 895)
      - Bibliographical files, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 896)
      - Bibliographical files, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 897)
      - Early drafts
        - Jacket description: typescript, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 898)
        - Outline and Introduction: holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 50, Folder 899)
        - Chapter I: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 900)
        - Chapter II: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 901-02)
        - Chapter III: holograph and typescript, corrected, with carbons (Box 50, Folder 903-11)
        - Chapter IV: holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 50, Folder 912-14)
        - Chapter V: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 915)
        - Chapter VI: holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 50, Folder 916-19)
        - Chapter VII: holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 50, Folder 920-21)
        - Chapter VIII: holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 51, Folder 922-24)
        - Chapter IX: holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 51, Folder 925-27)
        - Chapter X: holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 51, Folder 928-31)
        - Chapter XI: holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 51, Folder 932-33)
        - Chapter XII: holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 51, Folder 934-39)
        - Chapter XIII: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 940)
        - Chapter XIV: holograph and typescript, corrected (with comments by George Crile) (Box 52, Folder 941-50)
        - Chapter XV: holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 52, Folder 951-56)
        - Chapter XVI: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 957-59)
        - Chapter XVII: holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 52, Folder 960-64)
        - "List of Possible Illustrations", n.d. (Box 52, Folder 965)
        - Fragments, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 966)
      - "Author's Original Copy"
        - Typescript, [1962] (Box 53, Folder 967-73)
        - Typescript, carbon, corrected, [1962] (Box 53, Folder 974-80)
      - "Various Segments of Manuscript Used in Editing": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 981-86)
      - Revised draft: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 987-1003)
      - "Next-to-last version" (Chapter III only): typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1004)
      - Printer's typescript, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1005-13)
      - Galley proofs, [1962] (Box 55, Folder 1014-21)
      - Galley proofs, [1962] (Box 56 (Oversize), Folder 1022-23)
      - Page proofs (incomplete), 1962 (Box 56 (Oversize), Folder 1024)
        See also: Oversize, Box 117, folders 2208-10
      - Page proofs: "Author's set", 1962 (Box 56 (Oversize), Folder 1025-29)
      - Page proofs: second set, 1962 (Box 57 (Oversize), Folder 1030-32)
      - "Master Page Proofs", 1962 (Box 58 (Oversize), Folder 1033-38)
      - Printed copy (unbound signatures), 1962 (Box 59, Folder 1039-41)
      - Illustrations, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1042)
        See also: Oversize, Box 118, folders 2218-19
      - French edition ( Printemps Sans Voix ): typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1043-48)
      - German edition: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1049-57)
      - Icelandic edition ( Raddir Vorsins Pagna ): typescript, corrected, 1965 (Box 60, Folder 1058-62)
      - Spanish edition: ( Primavera Silenciosa ): typescript, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1063)
      - Serialization and abridgments
        - New Yorker
          - Page proofs
          - Printed copy, 1962 (Box 60, Folder 1064)
        - "Poisoned Water." Audubon Magazine, 1962 Sep-Oct (Box 60, Folder 1065)
        - "Beyond the Dreams of the Borgias." National Parks Magazine, 1962 Oct (Box 60, Folder 1066)
        - "A Beetle Scare, Spray Planes, and Dead Wildlife." Audubon Magazine, 1962 Nov-Dec (Box 60, Folder 1067)
        - "Rivers of Death" (Houghton Mifflin reprint), 1962 (Box 60, Folder 1068)
        - "La Natura Avvelenata." L'Europeo "La Morte Invisible." L'Europeo
          See: Oversize, Box 117, folders 2211-12
        - "Silent Spring." True Magazine, 1963 Apr (Box 60, Folder 1069)
        - Newspaper serializations, 1962-63 (Box 60, Folder 1070-73)
        - Excerpts, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1074)
    - Post-publication material
      - Reviews
        - List of newspaper and magazine reviews, 1962 (Box 61, Folder 1075)
        - "A" general, 1962 (Box 61, Folder 1076)
        - Associated Press, 1962 (Box 61, Folder 1077)
        - "B" general, 1962-63 (Box 61, Folder 1078-79)
        - "C" general, 1962-63 (Box 61, Folder 1080)
        - "D" general, 1962-63 (Box 61, Folder 1081)
        - "E" general, 1962 (Box 61, Folder 1082)
        - "F" general, 1962-63 (Box 61, Folder 1083)
        - "G" general, 1962-63 (Box 61, Folder 1084)
        - "H" general, 1962-63 (Box 61, Folder 1085)
        - "J" general, 1962-63 (Box 61, Folder 1086)
        - "K" general, 1062-63 (Box 61, Folder 1087)
        - "L" general, 1962-63 (Box 61, Folder 1088)
        - "M" general, 1962-63 (Box 61, Folder 1089)
        - "N" general, 1962 (Box 61, Folder 1090)
        - New York Times News Service, 1962 (Box 61, Folder 1091)
        - "O" general, 1962 (Box 61, Folder 1092)
        - "P" general, 1962-63 (Box 61, Folder 1093)
        - "R" general, 1962 (Box 62, Folder 1094)
        - "S" general, 1962-63 (Box 62, Folder 1095)
        - "T-U" general, 1962-63 (Box 62, Folder 1096)
        - UPI reviews, 1962 (Box 62, Folder 1097)
        - "V" general, 1962 (Box 62, Folder 1098)
        - "W" general, 1962-63 (Box 62, Folder 1099)
        - "Y" general, 1962 (Box 62, Folder 1100)
        - Unsigned reviews, 1962-63 (Box 62, Folder 1101-02)
        - British reviews, 1962-63 (Box 62, Folder 1103-04)
        - Canadian reviews, 1962 (Box 62, Folder 1105)
        - Foreign-language reviews, 1962-63 (Box 62, Folder 1106-11)
        - Review excerpts, 1962 (Box 62, Folder 1112)
        - Scrapbook (on Silent Spring and pesticide issues)
          See: Oversize, Box 116, folder 2207
      - Responses
        See also: Oversize, Box 116, folder 2207
        - "A" general, 1962-64, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1113-15)
        - Associated Press releases, 1962-63 (Box 63, Folder 1116)
        - "B" general, 1962-64 (Box 63, Folder 1117-25)
        - "C" general, 1962-64 (Box 63, Folder 1126-28)
        - "D" general, 1962-64 (Box 64, Folder 1129-31)
        - Douglas, William O., 1962 (Box 64, Folder 1132)
        - "E" general, 1962-63 (Box 64, Folder 1133-34)
        - "F" general, 1962-63 (Box 64, Folder 1135-38)
        - "G" general, 1962-70 (Box 64, Folder 1139-41)
        - "H" general, 1962-64 (Box 64, Folder 1142-44)
        - Houghton Mifflin defense, 1962-65, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1145-47)
        - "I" general, 1963, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1148)
        - "In Defense of Pesticides" (Boston Globe series), 1963 Feb (Box 64, Folder 1149)
        - "J" general, 1962-63 (Box 64, Folder 1150)
        - "K" general, 1962-63 (Box 65, Folder 1151-52)
        - "L" general, 1962-64 (Box 65, Folder 1153-54)
        - "M" general, 1962-64 (Box 65, Folder 1155-58)
        - Masters, Dexter. Foreword to Consumers Union edition, 1962 (Box 65, Folder 1159)
        - "N" general, 1962-63 (Box 65, Folder 1160-61)
        - New York Times News Service, 1962-63 (Box 65, Folder 1162)
        - "O" general, 1962-64 (Box 65, Folder 1163)
        - "P" general, 1962-64 (Box 65, Folder 1164-67)
        - "Q" general, 1963 (Box 65, Folder 1168)
        - "R" general, 1962-64 (Box 66, Folder 1169-72)
        - "S" general, 1962-64 (Box 66, Folder 1173-1180)
        - "T" general, 1962-64 (Box 66, Folder 1181-82)
        - "U" general, 1962-63 (Box 66, Folder 1183)
        - UPI releases, 1962-63 (Box 66, Folder 1184)
        - "V" general, 1962-63 (Box 66, Folder 1185)
        - "W" general, 1962-64 (Box 66, Folder 1186-88)
        - "X-Y" general, 1962-63 (Box 66, Folder 1189)
        - Chemical company responses, 1962-63 (Box 66, Folder 1190-92)
        - Compilations and excerpts, [1963] (Box 67, Folder 1193)
        - Unsigned responses, 1962-65 (Box 67, Folder 1194-1207)
        - Unsigned responses, 1962-65 (Box 68, Folder 1208-25)
        - Unsigned responses, 1962-65 (Box 69, Folder 1226-40)
        - Chronological responses, 1962 Nov (Box 70, Folder 1241-46)
        - British and Canadian responses, 1962-64 (Box 70, Folder 1247-49)
        - Foreign-language responses, 1963-65 (Box 70, Folder 1250)
        - "Letters to Editors", 1962-63 (Box 71, Folder 1251-66)
        - Cartoons, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1267-69)
      - Related material
        - Advance copy lists, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1270-72)
        - Awards and honors
          - Animal Welfare Institute: Schweitzer Medal, 1962-63 (Box 72, Folder 1273)
          - Carey-Thomas Award, 1962-63 (Box 72, Folder 1274)
          - National Audubon Society: Audubon Medal, 1963 (Box 72, Folder 1275)
          - National Book Award nomination, 1963 (Box 72, Folder 1276)
          - National Council of Women, 1963 (Box 72, Folder 1277)
          - Rod and Gun Association Award, 1963 (Box 72, Folder 1278)
          - Women's National Book Association: Constance Skinner Award, 1963 (Box 72, Folder 1279-80)
          - Other awards and honors, 1962-64 (Box 72, Folder 1281-82)
        - Best-seller lists, 1962-63 (Box 72, Folder 1283-84)
        - Best-seller lists, 1963 Jan-Jun (Box 73, Folder 1285-87)
        - "Congressional Hearings on Pesticides", 1963-64 (Box 73, Folder 1288-1300)
          See also: Box 74, folders 1322-23
        - "Congressional Hearings on Pesticides": Testimony of Rachel Carson, 1963 (Box 74, Folder 1301-02)
        - Effects of Silent Spring (legislative actions, etc.), 1962-70 (Box 74, Folder 1303-10)
        - Interviews, 1962-63 (Box 74, Folder 1311)
        - Library recommendations, 1962-64 (Box 74, Folder 1312)
        - [On Writing Silent Spring ], 1962 (Box 74, Folder 1313)
        - Parliamentary debates, 1951, 1963 (Box 74, Folder 1314-16)
        - Presentations and discussion groups, 1963-64 (Box 74, Folder 1317-21)
        - President's Science Advisory Committee, 1963 (Box 74, Folder 1322-23)
          See also: Box 73, folders 1288-1300
        - Promotional material, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 1324-28)
        - Publicity releases: Houghton Mifflin, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 1329)
        - Television debates
          "CBS Reports"
          - Typescript, 1963 (Box 75, Folder 1330)
          - Previews and announcements, 1962-63 (Box 75, Folder 1331-34)
          - Sponsorship controversy, 1963 (Box 75, Folder 1335)
          - Reviews, 1963 Apr (Box 75, Folder 1336-38)
          - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 1339)
          - "The Verdict of Silent Spring ", 1963 May (Box 75, Folder 1340-41)
          - Other television debates, 1963 (Box 75, Folder 1342-44)
      - Subject files
        - Air pollution, 1962, n.d. (Box 76, Folder 1345-46)
        - Birds, 1958-63 (Box 76, Folder 1347)
        - Drugs, 1962-63 (Box 76, Folder 1348)
        - Dutch Elm disease, 1962-63 (Box 76, Folder 1349)
        - Fire ants, 1962 (Box 76, Folder 1350)
        - Fish kills (general), 1963-64 (Box 76, Folder 1351-52)
        - Food and drug policies, 1962-64, n.d. (Box 76, Folder 1353)
        - Genetics, 1962 (Box 76, Folder 1354)
        - Green River fish kill, 1962 (Box 76, Folder 1355)
        - Industrial pamphlets, 1962-63, n.d. (Box 76, Folder 1356-59)
        - Mississippi River fish kill, 1964 (Box 76, Folder 1360-62)
        - Non-chemical insect control, 1962-63, n.d. (Box 76, Folder 1363)
        - Nutrition, 1962 (Box 76, Folder 1364)
        - Pesticide controls in England, 1963, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 1365)
        - Pesticide legislation, 1962-69, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 1366-67)
        - Pesticide pamphlets, 1963, 1965 (Box 77, Folder 1368)
        - Pesticide poisonings, 1962-64 (Box 77, Folder 1369)
        - Pesticides (general), 1962-69, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 1370-80)
        - Pesticides (chronological), 1962 Jul-1963 Apr (Box 78, Folder 1381-90)
        - Pesticides (chronological), 1963 May-Jun (Box 79, Folder 1391-1400)
        - Pesticides (chronological), 1963 Jun-Sep (Box 80, Folder 1401-09)
        - Pesticides (chronological), 1963 Oct-Dec (Box 81, Folder 1410-14)
        - Pesticides and gardens (Box 81, Folder 1415)
        - Pesticides and wildlife (Box 81, Folder 1416)
        - Pesticides: state and city programs (Box 81, Folder 1417-21)
        - Radiation, n.d. (Box 81, Folder 1422-23)
        - Sebago Lake pesticides, 1964 (Box 82, Folder 1424)
        - United States Senate. "Report of Proceedings...Environmental Hazards. Control of Pesticides and Other Chemical Poisons", 1963 (Box 82, Folder 1425-28)
        - Viruses, 1955 (Box 82, Folder 1429)
        - Water pollution, 1962 (Box 82, Folder 1430)
        - Weed control, 1964, n.d. (Box 82, Folder 1431)
        - Miscellaneous, 1952-64 (Box 82, Folder 1432-36)
      - Related correspondence
        - "A" general, 1962-64 (Box 83, Folder 1437-38)
        - American Forestry Association, 1963, n.d. (Box 83, Folder 1439)
        - Animal Welfare Institute, 1959-66 (Box 83, Folder 1440)
        - Atkinson, Brooks, 1962-63 (Box 83, Folder 1441)
        - "B" general, 1962-64 (Box 83, Folder 1442-43)
        - Barnes, Irston, 1961-62 (Box 83, Folder 1444)
        - Barnstead Still and Sterilizer Company, 1962 (Box 83, Folder 1445)
        - Biskind, Morton, 1962-65 (Box 83, Folder 1446-47)
        - Boston Nutrition Society, n.d. (Box 83, Folder 1448)
        - Briejèr, C. J., 1962 (Box 83, Folder 1449)
        - Brooks, Paul
          See: Houghton Mifflin, Boxes 87-89
        - "C" general, 1962-64 (Box 83, Folder 1450-51)
        - Cancerco (Cancer International Research Corp.), 1962 (Box 83, Folder 1452)
        - Canfield, Cass
          See: Harper and Brothers, Box 84, folder 1472
        - Cottam, Clarence, 1962-64 (Box 83, Folder 1453-56)
        - "D" general, 1962-64 (Box 83, Folder 1457)
        - Darling, Lois Darling, Louis, 1961-79 (Box 83, Folder 1458)
        - Diamond, Edwin, 1958, 1963 (Box 83, Folder 1459)
        - "E" general, n.d. (Box 83, Folder 1460)
        - Egler, Frank, 1962-63 (Box 84, Folder 1461-66)
        - "F" general, 1962-64 (Box 84, Folder 1467)
        - "G" general, 1959-64 (Box 84, Folder 1468)
        - Good, F. D. T., 1963-64 (Box 84, Folder 1469)
        - "H" general, 1962-64 (Box 84, Folder 1470-71)
        - Harper and Brothers, 1962-63 (Box 84, Folder 1472)
        - Huckins, Olga Huckins, Stuart, 1958-63 (Box 84, Folder 1473)
        - "I" general, 1962-64 (Box 84, Folder 1474)
        - Illinois. Natural History Survey, 1962-63 (Box 84, Folder 1475)
        - "J" general, 1962-63 (Box 84, Folder 1476)
        - "K" general, 1962-63 (Box 84, Folder 1477)
        - Kansas State Biological Survey, 1962 (Box 84, Folder 1478)
        - KPIX Television, 1963 (Box 84, Folder 1479)
        - "L" general, 1962-64 (Box 84, Folder 1480)
        - Lamb, Maila, 1963-64 (Box 84, Folder 1481)
        - Leake, Chauncey, 1962-63 (Box 84, Folder 1482)
        - Levine, Harold, 1963-64 (Box 84, Folder 1483)
        - Lindsey, A. A., 1962-63 (Box 84, Folder 1484)
        - "M" general, 1962-64 (Box 85, Folder 1485-86)
        - McCann, William S., 1962-63 (Box 85, Folder 1487)
        - Massachusetts Audubon Society, 1962-63 (Box 85, Folder 1488)
        - Merton, Thomas, 1963 Jan 12 (Box 85, Folder 1489)
        - Miller, Howard, 1962-63 (Box 85, Folder 1490)
        - Moot, Edward N., 1963 (Box 85, Folder 1491)
        - "N" general, 1962-63 (Box 85, Folder 1492)
        - National Audubon Society, 1962-64 (Box 85, Folder 1493-94)
        - The Nature Conservancy, 1963 (Box 85, Folder 1495)
        - The New Yorker, 1962 (Box 85, Folder 1496)
        - Nickell, Walter, 1963 (Box 85, Folder 1497)
        - Nutrition Foundation, 1963 (Box 85, Folder 1498)
        - "O" general, 1962-63 (Box 85, Folder 1499)
        - Orso, Leo, 1962-63 (Box 85, Folder 1500)
        - "P" general, 1962-64 (Box 85, Folder 1501)
        - "R" general, 1962-63 (Box 85, Folder 1502-03)
        - Reeves, Bruce, 1963 (Box 85, Folder 1504)
        - Ribicoff, Abraham, 1964-65 (Box 85, Folder 1505)
        - "S" general, 1962-64 (Box 85, Folder 1506-07)
        - Saturday Evening Post, 1963 (Box 85, Folder 1508)
        - Schulz, Charles, 1963 (Box 85, Folder 1509)
        - Scott, Ruth, 1962-64 (Box 85, Folder 1510)
        - Shackleton, Lord
          See: Box 87, folders 1623-24
        - Silver, Francis, 1909-63 (Box 85, Folder 1511-12)
        - The Star Magazine, 1962 (Box 85, Folder 1513)
        - "T" general, 1962-64 (Box 86, Folder 1514)
        - "U" general, 1963 (Box 86, Folder 1515)
        - Udall, Stewart, 1963 (Box 86, Folder 1516)
        - United States. Department of the Interior: Fish and Wildlife Service, 1963 (Box 86, Folder 1517)
        - United States. Department of the Interior: Office of the Secretary (Paul Knight), 1962-66 (Box 86, Folder 1518)
        - "W" general, 1962-64 (Box 86, Folder 1519)
        - Wallace, George J., 1962-64 (Box 86, Folder 1520)
        - Whelan, R. V., 1962-66 (Box 86, Folder 1521)
        - White, E. B., n.d. (Box 86, Folder 1522)
      - Editorial correspondence
        - Hamish Hamilton, Ltd., 1958 (Box 87, Folder 1523-24)
        - Houghton Mifflin Company, 1955 (Box 87, Folder 1525)
        - Houghton Mifflin Company, 1958 (Box 87, Folder 1526-27)
        - Houghton Mifflin Company, 1959 (Box 87, Folder 1528-31)
        - Houghton Mifflin Company, 1960 (Box 87, Folder 1532-38)
        - Houghton Mifflin Company, 1961 (Box 87, Folder 1539-43)
        - Houghton Mifflin Company, 1962 Jan-Jun (Box 87, Folder 1544-47)
        - Houghton Mifflin Company, 1962 Jul-Dec (Box 88, Folder 1548-55)
        - Houghton Mifflin Company, 1963 Jan-Mar (Box 88, Folder 1556-61)
        - Houghton Mifflin Company, 1963 Apr-Dec (Box 89, Folder 1562-70)
        - Houghton Mifflin Company, 1964-68 (Box 89, Folder 1571)
        - Houghton Mifflin Company, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 1572-73)
        - Houghton Mifflin Company: correspondence with National Agricultural Chemical Association, 1962 (Box 89, Folder 1574)
        - Houghton Mifflin Company: correspondence with Velsicol Corporation, 1962 (Box 89, Folder 1575)
      - Subject correspondence
        - Acknowledgments (form), 1962-63 (Box 89, Folder 1576-78)
        - Advance notices, 1962 (Box 89, Folder 1579)
        - "CBS Reports", 1962-63 (Box 89, Folder 1580)
        - Carbon dioxide, 1963 (Box 89, Folder 1581)
        - Congressional letters, 1963-64 (Box 89, Folder 1582)
        - Dieldrin, 1963 (Box 90, Folder 1583)
        - Dutch Elm disease, 1960-62 (Box 90, Folder 1584)
        - Educational use, 1962-63 (Box 90, Folder 1585)
        - Fire ant, 1961 (Box 90, Folder 1586)
        - Fish oil, 1963 (Box 90, Folder 1587)
        - Fluoridation, 1962-63 (Box 90, Folder 1588-89)
        - Gypsy moth, 1963 (Box 90, Folder 1590)
        - Illustrations for Silent Spring, 1962-63 (Box 90, Folder 1591-93)
        - Industrial correspondence, 1962 (Box 90, Folder 1594-95)
        - Japanese beetle, 1959-62 (Box 90, Folder 1596)
        - Livestock, 1962 (Box 90, Folder 1597)
        - Non-chemical insect controls, 1962-63 (Box 90, Folder 1598)
        - Personal appearances and lectures, 1962-64 (Box 90, Folder 1599)
        - Pesticide lawsuits, 1957-59, n.d. (Box 90, Folder 1600)
        - Pesticide legislation, 1963 (Box 90, Folder 1601)
        - Pesticide poisoning, 1962-64 (Box 90, Folder 1602)
        - Pesticides (Canada), 1963 (Box 90, Folder 1603)
        - Pyrethrum, 1962-63 (Box 90, Folder 1604)
        - Roadside spraying, 1963 (Box 91, Folder 1605)
        - Rocky Mountain Arsenal, 1962-63 (Box 91, Folder 1606)
        - Stream and lake poisoning, 1960-62 (Box 91, Folder 1607)
        - Toxic porphyria, 1962-63 (Box 91, Folder 1608)
      - Requests for information, n.d. (Box 91, Folder 1609-10)
      - Requests for reprints, 1962-63 (Box 91, Folder 1611-13)
      - Requests from students, 1963-64 (Box 91, Folder 1614-15)
      - Fan mail, 1962-64 (Box 91, Folder 1616-19)
      - Miscellaneous papers, 1962-64 (Box 91, Folder 1620-23)
      - Miscellaneous papers, 1962-64 (Box 92, Folder 1624-33)
  - A SENSE OF WONDER
    - Manuscripts
      - Woman's Home Companion ("Help Your Child to Wonder")
        - "Original Manuscript" draft: holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 93, Folder 1634)
        - Early draft
          - Holograph, n.d. (Box 93, Folder 1635)
          - Typescript (incomplete), n.d. (Box 93, Folder 1636)
        - Later drafts ("Help Your Child to Wonder"): typescripts, corrected (Box 93, Folder 1637-38)
        - Galley proofs, 1956 (Box 93, Folder 1639)
        - Printed copy
          See: Oversize, Box 117, folder 2213
        - French translation ("En vacances decouvrez avec votre enfant les merveilles de la nature"). Elle, 1956 Jul 20 (Box 93, Folder 1640)
      - Better Hearing ("Help Your Child to Wonder"), 1956 Autumn (Box 93, Folder 1641)
      - McCall's ("Help Your Child to Wonder")
        - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 93, Folder 1642)
        - Galley proofs, n.d. (Box 93, Folder 1643)
        - Printed copy
          See: Oversize, Box 117, folder 2214
      - Book version
        - Proposed chapter topics (letter to Marie Rodell): carbon, 1959 Jan 22 (Box 93, Folder 1644)
        - Typesetting copy, n.d. (Box 93, Folder 1645)
        - Galley proofs, 1964 Nov (Box 93, Folder 1646)
    - Post-publication material
      - Reviews, n.d. (Box 93, Folder 1647-50)
      - Promotional material, 1965 (Box 93, Folder 1651)
        See also: Oversize, Box 117, folder 2216
      - Television adaptation
        - Typescript, n.d. (Box 93, Folder 1652)
        - Publicity poster
          See: Oversize, Box 117, folder 2215
      - Related correspondence, 1955-61 (Box 93, Folder 1653)
      - Miscellaneous, 1965 (Box 93, Folder 1654)
  - SHORTER WORKS
    - Early Writings
      - "Just Dogs": typescript with correspondence, [1921] (Box 94, Folder 1655)
      - Undergraduate themes (Pennsylvania College for Women), 1925-28 (Box 94, Folder 1656-62)
      - M.A. Thesis, Johns Hopkins University: "Development of the Pronephros During the Embryonic and Early Larval Life of the Catfish (Ictalurus Punctatus)", 1932 (Box 94, Folder 1663)
    - Articles and Essays
      - "Ace of Nature's Aviators"
        - Notes and references, 1944, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 1664)
        - Typescripts, corrected, [1945] (Box 95, Folder 1665-66)
        - Coronet ("Sky Dwellers"), 1945 Nov (Box 95, Folder 1667)
        - Related correspondence, 1944-45 (Box 95, Folder 1668)
      - Animal Machines. By Ruth Harrison. Preface: typescript, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 1669)
      - "Are Pesticides Threatening the Nation's Health?": General Federation Clubwoman, 1963 Mar (Box 95, Folder 1670)
      - "Baltimore New Mecca for Nation's Sportsmen and Conservationists"
        - Typescript ("Baltimore Is Mecca for Conservationists this Week"), [1938] (Box 95, Folder 1671)
        - Baltimore Sun, 1938 Feb 13 (Box 95, Folder 1672)
      - "The Bat Knew It First"
        - Notes and references, 1943, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 1673)
        - Typescript and carbon (Box 95, Folder 1674)
        - Collier's, 1944 Nov 18 (Box 95, Folder 1675)
        - Related correspondence, 1944-45 (Box 95, Folder 1676)